<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>友ダッチ</title><link>https://tomodutch.com/en-us/</link><description>Recent content on 友ダッチ</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tomodutch.com/en-us/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to the coding project</title><link>https://tomodutch.com/en-us/posts/2022-05-27-coding-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Thomas</author><guid>https://tomodutch.com/en-us/posts/2022-05-27-coding-project/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I have some free time on my hands I wanted to learn some new technology so I bought some books from Humble Bundle about a variety of subjects. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in Rust, data science and machine learning. My goal is not te become an academic or even an expert on these topics. I&amp;rsquo;d like to dabble and know how to build solutions that may make learning Japanese easier or enhance other aspects of my life. Most of all I just want to have some fun and maybe it&amp;rsquo;ll turn into something others may find helpful as well. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll end up creating the same project in different programming languages hosted in a single monorepo like the &lt;a href="https://github.com/gothinkster/realworld">realworld project&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;m considering creating a single project on which I can apply what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="time-tracking">
&lt;a href="#time-tracking" class="anchor">
&lt;svg class="icon" aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" height="16" version="1.1" viewBox="0 0 16 16" width="16">
&lt;path fill-rule="evenodd"
d="M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z">
&lt;/path>
&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
Time tracking
&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d like to record how much time I&amp;rsquo;ve spend on learning certain subjects. For &amp;ldquo;human&amp;rdquo; language acquisition I&amp;rsquo;m using the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.teraculus.lingojournalandroid&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;gl=US">Lingo journal&lt;/a> app for my phone. I don&amp;rsquo;t really own any of the data and it&amp;rsquo;s not geared towards programming languages but I like its intuitive UI. A key feature for me are the definable goals. I&amp;rsquo;d like to spend some time studying the next few months and having clearly defined goals motivates me quite well. I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about creating an app with Flutter. I&amp;rsquo;ve also considered react native but like most developers pick their projects. Flutter has more stars than react native. Jokes aside, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with react native in the passed and I&amp;rsquo;d just like to do something new so it will be a nice challenge to write a cross platform app with the dart programming language.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="time-frame">
&lt;a href="#time-frame" class="anchor">
&lt;svg class="icon" aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" height="16" version="1.1" viewBox="0 0 16 16" width="16">
&lt;path fill-rule="evenodd"
d="M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z">
&lt;/path>
&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
Time frame
&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t have a concrete time frame but I&amp;rsquo;ll be hosting the repositories on my github account and will write about the project whenever I feel the need to update the world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spellcheckers in Visual Studio Code and the rare usage of Esperanto in tech</title><link>https://tomodutch.com/en-us/posts/2022-05-27-spell-checkers-and-esperanto/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Thomas</author><guid>https://tomodutch.com/en-us/posts/2022-05-27-spell-checkers-and-esperanto/</guid><description>
&lt;p>When I started writing this blog I figured I&amp;rsquo;d need to install a spellchecker. According to wikipedia I&amp;rsquo;m a native English speaker but unfortunately I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to acquire the ability to write a single article without errors. I installed the English spellchecker for my editor of choice namely visual studio code and for a reason unbeknownst to me the Esperanto variant has 233 downloads. There&amp;rsquo;s a rough estimate of two million &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Esperanto#:~:text=With%20up%20to%20two%20million,constructed%20language%20in%20the%20world.">Esperanto speakers&lt;/a> of which 233 felt the need like myself to install a spellchecker in visual studio code. The extension has no reviews either. I&amp;rsquo;d really like to get into contact with these 233 people and start a study about the purpose of installing an Esperanto spellchecker. Maybe Stack Overflow could include favorite &amp;ldquo;human&amp;rdquo; language in their yearly survey and ask a few questions to people who identify themselves as Esperanto speakers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I don&amp;rsquo;t live anywhere near an Esperanto speaking community I found a reddit post about the kinds of people who feel attracted to acquire Esperanto. Funny enough it seems that computer programmers are more inclined to do so. There&amp;rsquo;s also an &lt;a href="https://codemanship.wordpress.com/2020/04/06/is-uml-esperanto-for-programmers/">UML aficionado&lt;/a> that calls UML the Esperanto for computer programmers. I made an effort to find some usages of Esperanto in the tech space. I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to find documentation for a programming language written in Esperanto but if you find one feel free to leave a comment.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="esperanto-used-in-tech">
&lt;a href="#esperanto-used-in-tech" class="anchor">
&lt;svg class="icon" aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" height="16" version="1.1" viewBox="0 0 16 16" width="16">
&lt;path fill-rule="evenodd"
d="M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z">
&lt;/path>
&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
Esperanto used in tech
&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Esperanto/comments/ju0157/programming_might_be_the_biggest_obstacle/">Programming in Esperanto is challenging&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://mozilla-l10n.github.io/styleguides/eo/">Mozilla localization guide&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/crystal-lang/crystal/issues/2394">A proposal to use Esperanto as the default language in the Crystal programming language&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A &lt;a href="https://github.com/mkapiczy/vetero">few&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://github.com/sehwoo/fali">projects&lt;/a> that were named using Esperanto.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Interestingly enough the translation service &lt;a href="https://www.deepl.com/translator">deepl.com&lt;/a> doesn&amp;rsquo;t include Esperanto while google translate does. If you&amp;rsquo;re using postcss then you won&amp;rsquo;t have the ability to write css in Esperanto while css keywords are translated in &lt;a href="https://github.com/Kilian/postcss-dutch-stylesheets">many&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://github.com/ikkou/postcss-japanese-stylesheets">other&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://github.com/timche/postcss-german-stylesheets">languages&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And to top it all off there&amp;rsquo;s only a &lt;a href="https://github.com/trending?spoken_language_code=eo">single repository&lt;/a> on github that uses Esperanto which has 629 forks for no apparent reason because the README only states &amp;ldquo;HelperScript&amp;rdquo;. Which I don&amp;rsquo;t find particularly helpful at all.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://tomodutch.com/en-us/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Thomas</author><guid>https://tomodutch.com/en-us/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>
&lt;p>My name is Thomas and I grew up in the Netherlands. I&amp;rsquo;m planning to move to Japan in 2023 and have been studying the language for 3 years with various degrees of success. In order to practice my Japanese and have a place to write about my interests I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be fun to start this blog. I&amp;rsquo;ll be euphoric when I can write an excellent think piece but for the time being my articles will probably be quite small and specific so I can get the hang of this blogging thing.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>