<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tech on 友ダッチ</title><link>https://tomodutch.com/en-us/tags/tech/</link><description>Recent content in tech on 友ダッチ</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tomodutch.com/en-us/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to the coding project</title><link>https://tomodutch.com/en-us/posts/2022-05-27-coding-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tomodutch.com/en-us/posts/2022-05-27-coding-project/</guid><description>I have some free time on my hands I wanted to learn some new technology so I bought some books from Humble Bundle about a variety of subjects. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in Rust, data science and machine learning. My goal is not te become an academic or even an expert on these topics. I&amp;rsquo;d like to dabble and know how to build solutions that may make learning Japanese easier or enhance other aspects of my life.</description></item><item><title>Spellcheckers in Visual Studio Code and the rare usage of Esperanto in tech</title><link>https://tomodutch.com/en-us/posts/2022-05-27-spell-checkers-and-esperanto/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tomodutch.com/en-us/posts/2022-05-27-spell-checkers-and-esperanto/</guid><description>When I started writing this blog I figured I&amp;rsquo;d need to install a spellchecker. According to wikipedia I&amp;rsquo;m a native English speaker but unfortunately I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to acquire the ability to write a single article without errors. I installed the English spellchecker for my editor of choice namely visual studio code and for a reason unbeknownst to me the Esperanto variant has 233 downloads. There&amp;rsquo;s a rough estimate of two million Esperanto speakers of which 233 felt the need like myself to install a spellchecker in visual studio code.</description></item></channel></rss>